# Dipanjan Das

Security Researcher SecLab, UCSB

2015-2016

#### Research Interests

My research is directed towards developing novel analysis techniques to uncover vulnerabilities in low-level system software, *e.g.* operating system kernels and boot-loaders. To work on various exploit mitigation techniques for such targets to improve their practicality is in my future research plan.

#### Education

2016-Present	<b>Ph.D.</b> , <i>University of California</i> , Santa Barbara, <i>GPA - 4.0/4.0</i> . Computer Security, advised by Prof. Giovanni Vigna & Prof. Christopher Kruegel
2013-2015	<b>M.Tech.</b> , <i>Indian Institute of Technology</i> , Madras, <i>GPA – 8.81/10.0</i> . Computer Science & Engineering, advised by Prof. PanduRangan Chandrasekaran
2006-2010	B.Tech., Institute of Engineering & Management, Kolkata, GPA – 8.92/10.0.

## **Professional Experience**

Computer Science & Engineering

	·
2010-2012	Assistant Systems Engineer, Tata Consultancy Services (TCS), Kolkata, India.
2012-2013	<ul> <li>Scientist Engineer - SC, Gazetted Officer, Class 'A', Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO), Vikram Sarabhai Research Centre (VSSC), Trivandrum, India.</li> <li>To develop SPARCSIM, an instruction set simulator for a customized SPARC v8 based processor to be used on-board of next generation launch vehicles.</li> </ul>
2013-2015	Teaching Assistant, Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Madras, India.
2015-2015	Software Developer, BrowserStack, Mumbai, India.

Post-Graduate Research Intern, National University of Singapore, Singapore.

- Automatic patching of closed-source programs
   2017–2017 Interim Engineering Intern, Qualcomm Technologies, Inc, San Diego.
  - Developing a memory safe API in Rust to be used by *Qualcomm* drivers
    - O Developing an off-device fuzzing platform for a WLAN driver
- 2020–2020 Research Intern, University of Minnesota (Prof. Kangjie Lu), Minneapolis.
   Kernel fuzzing technique to trigger order-inconsistency bugs

#### **Publications**

- [7] P. Bose, **D. Das**, Y. Chen, Y. Feng, C. Kruegel, and G. Vigna, "Sailfish: Vetting smart contract state-inconsistency bugs in seconds," in *IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (IEEE S&P)*, 2022
- [6] N. Redini, A. Continella, D. Das, G. D. Pasquale, A. Machiry, A. Bianchi, C. Kruegel, and G. Vigna, "Diane: Identifying fuzzing triggers in apps to generate under-constrained inputs for iot devices," in *IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (IEEE S&P)*, 2021.
- [5] D. Song, F. Hetzelt, **D. Das**, C. Spensky, Y. Na, S. Volckaert, G. Vigna, C. Kruegel, J. P. Seifert, and M. Franz, "Periscope: An effective probing and fuzzing framework for the hardware-os boundary," in *BlackHat USA*, 2019.

- [4] D. Song, F. Hetzelt, **D. Das**, C. Spensky, Y. Na, S. Volckaert, G. Vigna, C. Kruegel, J. P. Seifert, and M. Franz, "Periscope: An effective probing and fuzzing framework for the hardware-os boundary," in *The Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS)*, This work was presented in Qualcomm Product Security Summit (QPSS), San Diego, CA, May 2019. **Was among the top 10 finalists in Applied Research Competition, CSAW, November 2019**, 2019
- [3] N. Redini, A. Machiry, **D. Das**, Y. Fratantonio, A. Bianchi, E. Gustafson, Y. Shoshitaishvili, G. Vigna, and C. Kruegel, "Bootstomp: On the security of bootloaders in mobile devices," in *Chaos Communication Congress (CCC)*, 2017.
- [2] N. Redini, A. Machiry, **D. Das**, Y. Fratantonio, A. Bianchi, E. Gustafson, Y. Shoshitaishvili, G. Vigna, and C. Kruegel, "Bootstomp: On the security of bootloaders in mobile devices," in *USENIX Security Symposium (Usenix)*, 2017.
- [1] P. Bose, **D. Das**, and C. P. Rangan, "Constant size ring signature without random oracle," in *Australasian Conference on Information Security and Privacy (ACISP)*, 2015.

### **Professional Activities**

- Reported five high-impact security vulnerabilities with financial consequences in OpenSea, Sorare, and Rarible NFT marketplaces (2021).
- Reported vulnerabilities CVE-2018-14745, CVE-2018-14852, CVE-2018-14853, CVE-2018-14854, CVE-2018-14855, CVE-2018-14856 to Samsung and CVE-2018-11947, CVE-2018-11902 to Qualcomm.
- Appears in CodeAurora Hall-of-Fame (2018) and Samsung Android Security Updates (August 2018).
- o Invited to Qualcomm Vulnerability Rewards Program at HackerOne (September 2018).
- Member of Shellphish Capture-The-Flag (CTF) team. Participated in DEFCON CTF Finals in the year 2017, 2018 and 2019.
- Member of the organizing team of UCSB iCTF security competition in the year 2017 and 2018.

#### Scholastic Achievements

- $\circ$  Stood  $29^{th}$  in  $X^{th}$  standard and  $16^{th}$  in  $XII^{th}$  state board examinations.
- ${\color{blue} \circ}$  Awarded by *Viren J. Shah*, ex-governor of West Bengal, for  $10^{th}$  rank in Kolkata zone in  $X^{th}$  standard board examination.
- O Received National Merit Scholarship twice from Ministry of Human Resource and Development (MHRD), Government of India for securing  $29^{th}$  position in  $X^{th}$  standard and  $16^{th}$  position in  $XII^{th}$  state board examinations.
- Secured all India rank 11 and 20 among 12,227 and 10,737 candidates in Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) entrance examination 2011 and 2014 respectively.
- Secured all India rank 106 among 2, 24, 160 candidates in GATE 2013.
- Received Presidential Graduate Fellowship at National University of Singapore (NUS).

#### **Academic Services**

Shadow PC	IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (IEEE S&P)	2021
	ACM SIGOPS in Europe (EuroSys)	2021
Program Committee	Usenix Security Symposium (Usenix) Artifact Evaluation	2022
External Reviewer	The Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS)	2022
Journal Reviewer	ACM Computing Surveys (CSUR)	2021

## Media Coverage

- Sep 2017 **ZDNet**, *Android security: Multiple bootloader bugs found in major chipset vendors' code*, for BootStomp [2].
- Sep 2017 **The Register**, *Boffins hijack bootloaders for fun and games on Android*, for BootStomp [2].
- Sep 2017 **The Hacker News**, *Mobile Bootloaders From Top Manufacturers Found Vulnerable to Persistent Threats*, for BootStomp [2].
- Sep 2017 NowSecure, Android bootloader security and BootStomp: A Primer, for BootStomp [2].
- Sep 2017 **Washington Center for CyberSecurity**, *BootStomp: Useful Tool in Researching Bootloaders*, for BootStomp [2].
- Aug 2017 PenTestlT, BootStomp: Find Mobile Device Bootloader Vulnerabilities, for BootStomp [2].
- Sep 2017 **ProgrammerSought**, BootStomp: About the bootloader security of mobile devices 6 BootStomp, for BootStomp [2].
- Sep 2017 SecurityWeek, Multiple Vulnerabilities Found in Mobile Bootloaders, for BootStomp [2].
- Dec 2017 **Pentest Tools**, *BootStomp A Bootloader Vulnerability Finder*, for BootStomp [2].
- Sep 2017 **NowSecure**, *Android bootloader security and BootStomp: A Primer*, for BootStomp [2].
- Sep 2017 **HebergementWebs**, *Experts discovered zero day flaws in Android bootloaders*, for BootStomp [2].
- Sep 2017 **Security Affairs**, https://securityaffairs.co/wordpress/62762/mobile-2/bootstomp-bootloaders-flaws.html, for BootStomp [2].
- Sep 2017 Hackers Online Club, BootStomp: An Android boot-loader Bug Finder, for BootStomp [2].
- Feb 2018 Quantus, BootStomp Find Android Bootloader Vulnerabilities, for BootStomp [2].